<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">-->
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://therightdoctors.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <title><![CDATA[TheRightDoctors]]></title>
        <link>https://therightdoctors.com/rss</link>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[Insights from the World's Best Medical Minds.Connect With Us to Connect With Them. We are a Digital Health Google LaunchPad Start-up.]]>
        </description>

        <image>
            <url>https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/logo.jpg</url>
            <title><![CDATA[TheRightDoctors]]></title>
            <link>https://therightdoctors.com/rss</link>
        </image>

        <language><![CDATA[en-us]]></language>

        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dr.Rishi Sethi: Pharmacoinvasive Approach- A Tool To Treat STEMI In The Peripheral Areas | STEMI India Lucknow 2018 | TheRightDoctors]]> </title>
            <link>https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-rishi-sethi-pharmacoinvasive-approach-a-tool-to-treat-stemi-in-peripheral-india</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-rishi-sethi-pharmacoinvasive-approach-a-tool-to-treat-stemi-in-peripheral-india</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Dr. Rishi Sethi, Prof of Cardiology, KGMU, Executive Council,
            Cardiological Society of India the man behind STEMI India Lucknow 2018 spoke to Hiral Bhat. This is what he said:
' Heart has coronary arteries supplying blood to heart muscles, whenever the arteries gets 100% blocked suddenly by thrombus,
it leads to infarction or death of that region of heart muscle'
'The success rate of opening the artery is between 50-80% by thrombolysis while by primary angioplasty it is more than 90%.'
" STEMI Is The Biggest Killer In India Especially In Rural Areas "
'Globally in developed countries, primary angioplasty is standard of care, however, for it to happen you need to have angioplasty centers all across the country'
'Any person who has a heart attack should be able to reach angioplasty centers within 1-6 hours from his chest pain, which is not possible in peripheral areas.'
" Angioplasty: Not Accessible In Peripheral Areas "
'Thrombolyse the patient first, establish flow in the blood vessels then shift the patient to an angioplasty center within 24 hours.'
'We should have thrombolytic, pharmacoinvasive and primary angioplasty setups across the country to reduce STEMI deaths.'
" STEMI India: Thrombolysis In Periphery & Stent In Cath Lab Within 24 hours "
]]> </description>
            <media:group>
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images/second-thumbnails/Rishi.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images/STEMIINDIA-2018/Rishi2/Rishi2-large.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />

            </media:group>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dr. VS Narain | STEMI India Lucknow 2018 | TheRightDoctors]]> </title>
            <link>https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-vs-narain-management-of-heart-attack-in-india-problems-and-solutions</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-vs-narain-management-of-heart-attack-in-india-problems-and-solutions</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[Dr.VS Narain, Professor & Head-Department Of Cardiology King George Medical University, Lucknow, spoke to Hiral Bhatt at
            STEMI India, Lucknow. This is what he said:
'The ideal STEMI management is to reperfuse the affected artery as soon as possible within the first hour which is possible in the west but not in India'
'If you thrombolyse within the first 3 hours, then the results are good, you are able to open up the artery and restore blood flow'
" STEMI Deaths In India Are More Than The West Due To Lack Of Funds & System "
'We have several peripheral hospitals, where thrombolysis is done immediately, then within the first 24 hours this patient is shifted to the
Hub Hospital where an angioplasty facility is available'
'Regarding the funding, in the West, a methodology has been developed in the southern part of India, you have identified the total costs that are going to
come for the entire population in that area and some insurance company takes up the challenge'
" STEMI India: Give Thrombolysis & Then PCI Within 24 Hours Of An Attack "
'We are working with STEMI India, where we would train the nurses, the technicians, the doctors and the specialist to create a Heart Attack Management Team.'
]]> </description>
            <media:group>
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images/STEMIINDIA-2018/Dr-VS-Narain/Dr-VS-Narain-large.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images/second-thumbnails/VS-Narain.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />

            </media:group>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title> <![CDATA[Dr. ZS Meherwal: Ventricular Septal Defect- Meaning, Causes & Treatment | STEMI India Lucknow 2018 | TheRightDoctors]]></title>
            <link>https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-zs-meherwal-mi-ventricular-septal-defect-rare-but-fatal</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-zs-meherwal-mi-ventricular-septal-defect-rare-but-fatal</guid>
            <description> <![CDATA[Dr. ZS Meherwal, Director of Cardiovascular Surgery, Fortis Escort Hospital, Delhi, spoke to Hiral Bhat at STEMI India 2018, Lucknow. This is what he said:
' Ventricular septal defect is not a very common condition It is rare, but at the same time, it is very devastating.'
'With the introduction of thrombolysis and PCI, the incidence has reduced to less than 0.5%, but the mortality is still high.'
'Ventricular septal rupture needs to be diagnosed in time and the best way to diagnose would the echocardiography.'
'After a diagnosis of the ventricular septal defect, we stabilize the patient by medications and intra aortic balloon pump and operate these patients.'
'Intraoperatively we have good techniques to repair the ventricular septal defect and to repair the ventricle which is infracted by proper revascularization by coronary artery bypass grafting.']]></description>
            <media:group>
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images-extra/Dr-ZS-Meherwal-large.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images-extra/Dr-ZS-Meherwal-large.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />
            </media:group>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title> <![CDATA[Dr. Thomas Alexander : The STEMI India Model has Reduced Deaths By 22 percentage| STEMI India Lucknow 2018 | TheRightDoctors]]></title>
            <link>https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-thomas-alexander-the-stemi-india-model-has-reduced-deaths-by-22-percentage</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-thomas-alexander-the-stemi-india-model-has-reduced-deaths-by-22-percentage</guid>
            <description> <![CDATA[Dr. Thomas Alexander, Senior Interventional Cardiologist and a founding director of STEMI India, Head of Division of Cardiology Kovai Medical Center And Hospital,
            Coimbatore spoke to Hiral Bhatt t at STEMI India 2018, Lucknow. what he said:
' Tamil Nadu STEMI program was a program that was sponsored by the Indian Council of Medical Research it is now known as STEMI India model which really is the hub and spoke model.'
" STEMI India Hub & Spoke Model: ECG In Periphery & Treatment In The Cath Lab "
'A Hub hospital with a Cath Lab is connected to multiple peripherals centers and these were linked electronically using a device that we call the STEMI kit.'
'It handholds the physicians in a small hospital and starts treatment early in case of a heart attack.'
" The Model Trains Doctors To Treat STEMI & Is 60% Funded By The Government "
'This model is unique and within a period of 9 months we reduced mortality by 22%. These models are very cost intense, you need very high quality of doctors.'
'The government of India will pay 60% of the cost of setting up this program. '
" The Model Has Benefited The Peripheral Areas And Reduced Deaths By 22% "]]></description>
            <media:group>
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images-extra/thomas-large.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images-extra/thomas-large.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />
            </media:group>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title> <![CDATA[Dr. PP Mohanan: Oral Treatment For Managing STEMI And Reducing Deaths | STEMI India Lucknow 2018 | TheRightDoctors]]></title>
            <link>https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-pp-mohanan-newer-molecules-have-helped-in-treating-stemi-patients</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">https://therightdoctors.com/stemi-india-lucknow-2018/the-interview/stemi-india-tv-dr-pp-mohanan-newer-molecules-have-helped-in-treating-stemi-patients</guid>
            <description> <![CDATA[Dr. P P Mohanan. Director and head of the Department of Cardiology, Westfort Hospital, Thrissur, Kerala.
            spoke to Hiral Bhatt t at STEMI India 2018, Lucknow. This is what he said:
' Newer molecules or new oral anticoagulants have helped in treating STEMI. We have been using the dual antiplatelet drugs, which involve the aspirin and clopidogrel.'
'If one uses an intravenous preparation of aspirin in the dose of 250 to 500 mg, it may be better than the conventional oral dose of aspirin.'
" Antiplatelet Drugs: Helps In Treating STEMI Orally "
'There are Ticagrelor & Prasugrel as well but systemic analysis shows that maybe Ticagrelor is a better drug than Prasugrel in STEMI management.'
'We have been using Heparin for the last many years. Heparin is efficient and is commonly used worldwide during STEMI treatment.'
" Ticagrelor, An Antiplatelet Drug Has Reduced Death Rate Considerably "
'There is a drug like fondaparinux which we use but not in the Cath lab for the Fondaparinux has its value in STEMI patients who undergo fibrinolytic treatment.'
'Right now in the Cath Lab, in STEMI management, the principal anticoagulant used is Heparin.'
" Anticoagulants Also Help In Curing STEMI. Heparin Is The Most Used Drug "]]></description>
            <media:group>
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images/second-thumbnails/PP-Mohanam.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />
                <media:content medium="image" url="https://storage.googleapis.com/web-assets/images/STEMIINDIA-2018/Dr-PP-Mohanan/Dr-PP-Mohanan-large.jpg" height="619" width="1100" />
            </media:group>
        </item>

    </channel>
</rss>